ellie fairholm

Full-Stack Developer specialising in Javascript. Curiosity for learning new technologies. Currently writing a programming book on how to deploy an Elixir application from development to production. Highly motivated and always positive. Flexible approach and effective communicator in order to meet demanding deadlines.

Skills

Javascript | Node.js | AWS | Severless | MongoDB | SQL | GraphQL | React | Redux | Express.js Jest | Cypress.io | Optimism | Teamwork | Adaptability | Communication | Flexibility | Mentor

Professional Experience

Imagen Therapeutics, Full Stack Developer

03/2022 - 03/2023

- Biotech company personalising clinical cancer diagnoses and accelerating drug discovery.

London

- Responsibilities: Developing and maintaining a client portal displaying database information and scientific data visualisations. Updating deprecated code and architecting a new database deployment. Learnt self-management and project organisation.

- Tech stack: React, D3, Azure, Node.js, MongoDb.

Abi Global Health Limted., Client Integration Developer

2020 - 03/2022 London / Barcelona

 $\hbox{-} Microconsultation service for users to ask health questions to medical professionals.}$

- Responsibilities: Integrating new clients' technologies into our existing system. Curating custom client landing pages and ensuring comprehensive front-end testing. Automating the integration process. Improving microservice and API structures. Learnt how to write effective documentation and to deliver high quality work on a tight schedule.

- Tech stack: React, AWS, Node.js, Serverless, MySQL.

noREST, Full-Stack Software Engineer

2020 - 2020

- Service platform that lets you create a comprehensive no-code API in minutes.

Barcelona

- Responsibilities: led a back-end team and designed the underlying data infrastructure, flow and caching. Learnt the importance of communication and optimism.
- Tech stack: React, Redux, Material UI, Node.js, Koa, Mongoose, MongoDB, Redis.

Magic Mirror Widget: on-this-day, Back-End Software Engineer

2019 - 2020

- Open-source module for MagicMirror² that displays a daily historical fact using my own public API.
- Barcelona

- Tech Stack: Node.js, Koa, Mongoose, MongoDB.

Education

Codeworks, Europe's Leading Javascript Bootcamp

2019 - 2020

- Intensive 3 month, 65 hrs a week programming course.

Barcelona

- Front-End and Back-End Javascript Frameworks: React, Node.js, SQL and NoSQL databases.

University of Exeter, History and Spanish

2015 - 2019

- Mastering of writing skills and an extensive study of 20th Century social world history.

Exeter

- Spanish fluency with a year abroad in Barcelona.

St George's College Weybridge, A* A* A

2008 - 2015

- Academic Scholarship.

London

- Mentor to younger and new students.

Languages

English Spanish French

Native language Full working proficiency - C1 Limited working proficiency - B1

Interests

Tap DancingBalletHockeyAdvanced 2 ISTD qualification.Grade 8 RAD qualification.County level.

ellie fairholm elliefairholm@gmail.com